# 現在越來越瘦了天氣又熱 容易中暑哦
They're getting skinnier every day. And it's so hot. It's easy to get heat stroke.
# 還不如
Why don't we,
# 抓兩個來把它吃了再說
catch two ducks and eat them before anything goes wrong?
# 好瘦啊
It's so skinny!
# 你看
Look!
# 這個鴨
This duck,
# 好輕啊 現在
weighs nothing now.
# 可能只有三斤左右
I think it's only around a kilogram and a half.
# 不夠吃啊 一個 再搞一個來
It's not enough to feed us, this one alone. Let me catch one more.
# 再抓一個
I'm gonna catch one more.
# 先把它抓住它
Hold it first!
# 你看 這兩個鴨子 如困不把它宰掉的話它越來越瘦的
Look! These two ducks, would only be skinnier if they're left here any longer.
# 現在都好輕啊 現在 可能只有兩三斤了
Now they weigh almost nothing now. I think they should be just around a kilogram or one and a half.
# 看上去毛多 等下我拔那個毛就可以看很到
They seem to be covered with a lot of feather. But we'll see after defeathering them,
# 身上沒甚麼肉的
that there's not much meat on their bodies.
# 味道絕對OK
The taste must be absolutely OK.
# 你看 這兩隻鴨子
Look! These two ducks...
# 這個都更死怖啦 那麼小
This one is even more awful. It's so small.
# 沒辦法
Anyway
# 這個還可以
This one is not too bad.
# 再不 再 再不吃的話就
If it's, if, if it's left any longer here,
# 這個再不吃的話就像這個一樣
it would become like this one if this one is left any longer.
# 這不虧大了 這樣
It would be a great loss. Really
# 好 拿去
Alright! Take them to...
# 拿廚具來
I'm gonna get the cookers.
# 我先把它處理一下
Let me do some processing first.
# 給它取下內臟
So I remove the guts.
# 那邊太熱啦
It's too hot over there.
# 我到這邊來
So I come to this side.
# 不要中暑了 那就很麻煩啦
I don't wanna get heat stroke. It would be too much of a trouble.
# 洗手啊 可以 就這裡洗 過來一點
Wanna wash you hands? Sure! Wash here. Come closer!
# 再過來一點
A bit more closer
# 好啦好啦好啦 衣服都洗濕啦
Alright, alright, alright. You're getting your clothes wet.
# 這個要把它砍碎
It needs to be chopped into pieces.
# 這個刀
This knife,
# 磿利了就是快
works so well after it's sharpened.
# 先把它翅膀 砍掉
The wings first. Chop them off!
# 終於搞定啦 把它砍碎啦
Done finally. It's chopped into piece now.
# 你看 這鍋已經燒熱哦
Look! The wok is heated now.
# 燒熱了 不要這個水
It's hot now. I'm gonna pour the water away.
# 放點油
'kay. Put some oil.
# 油都沒啦
No more oil now.
# 火還不夠猛 搞猛一點的火
The fire is still not strong enough. I gotta make it stronger.
# 先炒一下這 先炒一下這個鴨子 然後再來燜
Let me first fry the, fry the duck for a while first, and then stew it.
# 這個鍋 開始熱啦
This wok, is getting hot now.
# 把這個鴨 把這個鴨肉 炒一下
The duck, the duck meat, I fry it for a while.
# 哇 差不多啦
Wa! It should be done.
# 誒喲
Eyo!?
# 搞破啦
I broke it.
# 沒事
No worries
# 倒一瓶下去
I pour one bottle,
# 先倒一瓶下去
pour one bottle first.
# 倒不出啦 沒啦
It's not coming out. No more
# 一瓶酒怎麼那麼少
Why so little? Isn't it a whole bottle of beer?
# 嗯 這個要小心點放
Um. This one needs to be handled with care.
# 倒兩瓶 一瓶不夠
Let me put two bottles. One is not enough.
# 你看 這支就開好啦
Look! This bottle is very nicely opened.
# 搞點啤酒
Put some beer
# 哎呦 好大的啤酒味呀
Ayo! A strong scent of beer.
# 你看 怎麼倒都倒不完
Look! Why is it never ending?
# 啊 這個才靚啊 這個
Ah! So it's really beautiful now, really.
# 燒火 燜它
Stew, on the fire
# 八角 放兩個八角下去
Star anise, put a couple of star anise.
# 再搞點
And also some...
# 搞點辣椒乾下去 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Put some dried chilli.
# 你看 好像啤酒不夠 再搞一瓶下去
Look! The beer doesn't seem enough. Let me put one more bottle,
# 搞醉它去
to make it drunk.
# 啤酒還不夠 來給它洗一下澡
There's still not enough beer. Let me give it a bath.
# 再搞一瓶
One more bottle
# 哇 好香啊
Wa! It smells so good!
# 爸爸你幹甚麼
What are you doing, Daddy?
# 我在幹甚麼是不是 我在燜鴨鴨
Did you ask me what I'm doing? I'm stewing the duckies.
# 要不要等下吃
You want some in a while?
# 要吃 是不是
You want, don't you?
# 好 等一下來啊
Alright! A moment
# 燜好了就一起吃啊
We can enjoy together when it's done.
# 鹽都忘記放了
I've even forgotten to put salt.
# 搞多一點
A bit more
# 哎呦 都要粘鍋了
Ayo! It's sticking onto the wok.
# 剛剛好
Just right!
# 來的剛剛好
Perfect timing!
# 剛好收汁 收完啦
The sauce has just thickened, just right.
# 你看
Look!
# 好靚哦 我澆一下水
Beautiful! Let me rinse it.
# 色香味俱全
To be enjoyed with eyes, nose and taste buds
# 絕對好吃
It's absolutely tasty.
# 爸爸 誒
Daddy!
Ey~
# 好辣
Spicy!
# 嗯 很辣 等一下 你坐在那裡等一下啊
Um! It's really spicy. A moment. You wait for a moment, sitting over there.
# 我吃完就來啊
I'll come to you after finishing it.
# 哎呀 有點辣 這個
Aya! It's a bit spicy, really.
# 很好吃的哦
It's so tasty, you know.
# 是不是你也想吃是不是
You want some, right? Don't you?
# 你看 全是瘦肉
Look! It's all lean meat.
# 給這大肥狗 誒呦 小黑那麼厲害
Give to this big fat dog. Eyo? Why is Blacky so skillful?
# 啊 嘶~ 就是有點燙 (註︰這個「嘶」有點難搞，這是碰熱東西時的聲音，一般是吸氣的)
Wa! Shi~ But it's a bit too hot.
# 嗯 等一下我給個給你吃啊
Um! I'll give you one in a while.
# 真的很好吃哦 不騙你們的
It's really tasty. I'm not kidding.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡了
Alright! The video ends here.
# 這個鴨子 真的太好吃啦
This duck, is simply too tasty.
# 在我這裡減 減肥減了兩個月
They've been on, on a diet for two months here at my place.
# 夠瘦了
They're slim enough now.
# 所以這
That's why,
# 味道
the taste,
# 特別好吃
is exceptionally good.